like the the country ones that like
there's co.uk and.uk and. co.jp and. JP
and I think there's a couple other that
are like that but then the US is just us
yeah I don't know why yeah maybe we just
have do I is that a us you know is did
that origin origin climate man [__]
right it's ours
[Music]
now
sup my dude yo yo yo man what a day dude
I know man it's just me and you again no
more guests we've been doing guest paloa
this past couple episodes I know yeah I
feel like n up I'm I'm at the I'm at the
standing desk right now this might be
this might might be a sitting episode
not going to lie cuz it's just been so
freaking crazy lately hold on let me we
even go into the my standing desk chaos
oh my god dude tell the people about
that while I go get my chair Yeah so
basically I have an uplift desk I love
my uplift desk it's a huge it's like the
biggest sit standand desk I could find
it's some it's like 90 inches long or
something I I don't know how many feet
or meters that is uh it's big it's huge
and uh it's been great for like a couple
years and then yesterday we were doing
some recording and uh I was I was like
noticing that my camera was like slanted
it was so off and I was like I don't
know what's causing this and I had I
like rotated my monitor so it looks
straight and I was like that's
definitely crooked and so I just like
ignored it and figured it was like maybe
my house is out of level or something
and so then I just like sat down while
my desk was up and I was like sitting in
my chair and I just look over at my desk
and I see it's like visibly like slight
like very noticeably at a different
height and it turns out the legs were at
different heights so then I tried to fix
it and I like lowered the whole thing
down and then it started throwing this
error code and I like looked up the
error code and they were like you should
try and reset your system and I like did
the I did don't don't skip the the part
where Joel was angrily filling out like
a warranty agreement you know Joel's
like God this stupid piece of garbage
like I gotta I gotta like submit a
warranty claim on this bloody blood BL
I'm like Joel did you try like holding
the down arrow for a little while here's
the thing here's the thing here's the
thing I reset it by holding like the the
way you're supposed to do it is you hold
the down arrow and then it like it's
supposed to bring both legs all the way
down if they're at different levels and
I did that but then it threw this error
code and so it was like if you see this
error code and like it wouldn't do
anything with the like I couldn't move
it I couldn't like I unplug why did it
start working whenever I
said I'm getting there I'm getting there
okay so I fill out I like do the reset
instructions nothing Chang changes I'm
like okay this is like broken I need to
have them fix this I guess and also my
desk is now slanted and stuck in the
down stck on a slanted yeah that was so
bad so I like I fill out this forum I
like take pictures and stuff I send it
all off then you're like have you tried
like just holding down and like usually
that's how you're supposed to like
recalibrate it but I figured it wouldn't
do anything because it was in the airor
mode so I like try it and sure enough it
goes into like ASR or whatever and then
I'm able to hold down and the other leg
like went all the way down finally and
then I like recalibrated it and
everything is working fine now so I I
don't even know I feel like an idiot cuz
you got to go cancel your warranty claim
bro I know I and I feel like an idiot
because I I like sent them an email or
whatever I like filled out their form
and then like 20 minutes later I said a
follow I was like yeah actually never
mind I fixed it uh so anyways well that
that's uh that's another episode of
Joel's office problems we've talked
about chairs we've talked about we've
talked about cameras and mics and and
now we've got a started on cameras don't
get me started on cameras you saw the
white balance problems with my camera
yester I did dude you had to fight with
those that was a challenge um all right
let's give the people what they're
looking for here Joel let's give them uh
some talk about security about critical
vulnerabilities or in this case uh our
our boy xnl hacker dropping a pretty
awesome Chrome extension um inspired by
the Pod and inspired by some some tweets
from the podcast account um after the
episode with renie Pac he was he was
thinking actually he does a nice write
up of his sort of thought thought
process or inspiration in in the GitHub
repo but he releases this um Chrome
extension called xnl reveal which um
shows alerts for any query parameters
that are
reflected um shows any hidden elements
and uh enables any disabled elements and
and Joel I don't know if you saw it
because I was running the Twitter at the
time did you see that whole tweet storm
about like um you know enabling hidden
elements via a Chrome extension versus
you know using burps enabled thing I did
I didn't see any of this and one
interesting thing I will note as well on
that feature specifically is that in
like the latest I think it's the latest
version or whatever Point version. 3 um
he made a change where now it's like a
context menu so if you right click
there'll be a little button to show
hidden elements so it doesn't show it by
default on everything which I think is
probably for the better uh just for
usability but no I didn't see uh I
didn't see that so essentially the whole
the whole concept of that that tweet was
like
um you know burp has this feature where
it will modify the H uh HTML response to
remove any like disabled equals true or
like you know some of the hidden
features right um to hide an HTML
element so you can access stuff like
buttons that shouldn't be clickable that
sort of thing but the majority of the
apps nowadays are being generated by
like a like a JavaScript um you know
single page thing right so um when HTML
elements are being generated on the
client side uh it's bypassing that whole
thing with burp so you're missing a
bunch of hidden elements so I actually
have in order in order to solve this I
actually have a JavaScript bookmark lit
that I use where I click this bookmark
lit and then it automatically goes
through and like removes anything with
display non or like removes the disabled
elements but xnl hacker combined
that piece of advice or that that sort
of conversation that we had on Twitter
with um the stuff that uh reny Pax was
talking about on the episode we did uh
live from from Portugal and created this
awesome extension that does it all so
really nice really nice work there man
really like that xnl hacker yeah yeah
that's awesome that it was really cool
to see and it looks like it really like
popped off on Twitter it's got like a
ton of views and a ton of stars on on uh
on GitHub so it's really cool to see the
community like hearing us talk about
these of things and then going and just
spinning up a tool in a day or two like
it's really awesome I know man whenever
anybody does that I like I'm so excited
and happy because it's like I feel like
I contributed to that but I didn't you
know like I get to like sort of be like
yeah I it's like that that Meme you know
like that I made this this yeah like I
love that that's great yeah that's
awesome yeah uh all right cool uh did
you get a chance to read this next one I
didn't but uh we have a couple things
about like email uh and ooth account
takeovers and stuff so uh why don't you
why don't you break this down cuz we
have one follow up yeah yeah this one's
this one's a cool one okay um so this is
a write up VI salt Labs okay and this is
discussing a ooth problem that affected
uh a lot of a lot of websites it looks
like uh they were able to exploit three
websites with this um
vulnerability and whenever anything ooth
pops up I'm listening because it it's
it's widely used everywhere and uh it's
so complicated and I know that there's
some stuff I don't understand about this
right because you know dang well you
probably know the people I'm talking
about but there are some people that are
at the live hacking events that like
oath is their thing and they're just
like so you know mysterious about it and
you know I've gone up to him a couple
time I've been like yo so tell me what
what the deal is and they're like can't
tell you man like the heck so on this
like never- ending search to understand
oath as well as these people um so this
one definitely caught my attention uh
but it but it's a little bit um it's a
little bit different from like a normal
oath configuration thing it's actually
specific to Facebook and I and I imagine
that there are other providers that
might have similar vulnerabilities but
the concept here was that um whenever
using Facebook to log in uh you know a
user right so this is U AFF a
vulnerability affecting application that
allow sign on from via Facebook log in
with Facebook um there's a little caveat
down down the you know line in the
instructions for how to build this out
that says when you get a token back from
the user you need to make a uh
introspection call to make sure that
this token is for your own your own um
app rather than for a different app
right nor a weird thing to call out it
it is it is you know like you think that
they would do this but in but in the
beginning I was thinking like oath okay
so shouldn't they have to like swap the
code for like an access token but that's
actually a different oath flow that's
the the um well actually I I shouldn't
speak to it off the top of my head
because I I believe that this one is
called the explicit Grant type but but
essentially the the the big thing that
changes here in the end is that the
response type is different right they
they give you a token at the end rather
than a code which the um user needs to
give to the server side and and then
thus have swap for an access token in
instead they just give the access token
directly to the website right so when
you see this in these sort of situations
what they're supposed to do is take this
access token and hit a debug endpoint to
be like okay is this access token for my
app or or is it for a different app
right and um if it's for a different app
and they they don't do this check then
they can just continue you know reaching
out to slashme or whatever grab the
email down right from slme and then just
B that user in which is so weird because
you you think that from the like from
the backend side they would basically
just check if you're authorized to be
making calls with a token for another
app
and well guess there's no delation
that's the off token now that's what I
thought too when I was thinking because
because when you swap the code right
normally you would be using your server
secret right plus the code to get the
token right but in this scenario you're
actually just giving the server side the
token and that's the token that they use
to contact Facebook a really sus like
setup honestly
it is it is a little sus but um I think
it's a really I think it's a really cool
bug you know that they understood ooth
well enough to to piece all this
together so you know the the only so
this allows you to do um account
takeover with the with the one caveat
that the you have to have that user um
be you know the user whose account you
want to take over it h they have to be a
customer of your Facebook app so that
you can generate a token for that user
right okay um and so that kind of liting
it is limiting for sure but let's say
you know there there are so many stupid
Facebook apps man right like you know
the you know Facebook you know adjacent
things right and how easy would it be to
go pop those and then use those to sign
into something like grammarly which is
um you know one of the the people that
was uh vulnerable to this attack so uh
really really cool bug here with a
technique that I hadn't seen before um
and definitely going to be keeping an
eye out for this in the
future yeah I mean I know gramarly has a
100K Bounty for what is it it has to be
zero click though right yeah it has to
be zero click man they were so close I
have heard a lot of a lot of cases where
uh people have been like one click or
like basically like you click on a link
or like you load a link or something and
like kind of zero click um but uh
nothing's ever qualified as far as I
know yeah man this one was super close
you know like this is this is for
me for me this is like I think this
would land on the user interaction not
required side of you know if I had to
pick between not required or required I
would actually put this in not required
personally you you you could make an
argument for attack complexity high for
sure but I wouldn't put this as user
interaction required yeah I would agree
because you know the attack complexity
is really that they have to like for one
you have to like basically pop like a an
app that they already have authorized
which may or may not be difficult
depending on what they sign in with but
there is definitely some extra
interaction they're required to like
whether whether it's directly I think
user interaction I would usually count
as like as part of the bug it has to be
that like yeah the user has to interact
they don't have to interact for this to
be exploited but they have to have done
something else for it to be exploitable
dude speaking of that should we uh
should we talk about this like crazy
drama that's going on right now uh with
the hacktivity hacker one hacktivity
thing where that guy got like robbed
based off of a CVS assess did you see
that I I I saw a bunch of uh of like
chatter about it and being like this is
not how this should have been handled
and and all that kind of stuff but I
didn't actually read the report yeah I
just dm'd it to you on on on Discord
Let's uh let's let's take a pause I know
I know be which is funny because beik
actually replied to this last week sweet
but what we just talking about um so
yeah this is this is a a pretty
interesting situation and at the end of
the day like you
can't is this this is the one with be
with bevic right yeah yeah I see it
right here okay um at the end of the day
people make mistakes and stuff right and
I I I fully expect that hacker one will
will fix this mistake personally it
hasn't happened yet but I I I ful expect
they will this user reported
uh they were doing something cool right
which I which I've talked about in the
Pod before which is monitoring the JS
files of an application for changes
right and they noticed that a new Google
doc link appeared right and when they
went to that Google doc link they found
that the attacker has the ability to
edit anything and see some confidential
data about other users you know emails
and survey responses and stuff like this
right so it's a pretty decent leak um
and then check out check out this
comment halfway down by
yeah yeah they recategorized it saying
that the attack complexity was high
because the attacker is monitoring the
code base and the associated Google form
had to be published to the codebase by
internal staff
yeah wrong but okay user interaction
required a staff member owns the form
Mis configured permissions which led to
being able to access the confidential
data when in possession of the
link okay how does that yeah the so
here's here's here's here's what I'm
going to say I understand where he's
coming from I'm sorry you're wrong yeah
the user and the attack complexity does
not matter when you're the one who
created the vulnerability the attack
complexity is not that you created a
vulnerability it's how hard is it to
exploit exactly so these sort of things
they happen they happen to you know
triers working at hacker one they happen
on the program levels if this doesn't
get fixed I'm going to I'm going to
holler more you know but um if they
wanted to if they didn't want to pay out
higher than this they could say that it
was um you know confidentiality low
right rather than high I would say that
it is high personally but I would say
you know you could say confidentiality
low and that would drop the the impact
but uh attack complexity High user
interaction required not a chance for
this yeah no I I totally agree that's uh
that's pretty interesting I'll be
interested to see
if they decide to reevaluate that
hopefully they do I think it deserves a
reevaluation I think it's kind of I mean
if nothing else uh I don't think it
aligns with like how theyve handled
things in the past and how they view
sity as a whole so um we'll see we'll
see what happens it looks like it was
disclosed four days ago so the the storm
is still building and it was you know it
was over the weekend a little bit too so
and I I've I've reached out to hacker
one you know whenever this sort of thing
happens I'll I'll reach out and be like
hey you know just FYI you're getting
roasted on Twitter here you know but uh
but um you know hopefully we'll see a
change here and to the person that made
a mistake on this one happens we just
got to make it right you know there's
there's no there's no ill will here you
know at least from from the critical
thinking side we understand that these
sort of mistakes happen but when they do
happen hopefully they get resolved um
this this this report actually um I
guess was submitted on September 25th so
it's been over a month in this state if
I was uh you know I don't know how to
pronounce this person be be Beck see man
I don't know why when it's not a word I
just have such a hard time pronouncing
it yeah um when you know if I were bck
I'd be pretty I'd be pretty salty at
this point but uh it seems like they've
been taking it in stride um and even
asking to disclose the report so yeah
we'll see if the community gets their
voice heard on this one F yeah
absolutely and and based on some
discussions in the hacker success um
manager the server on Discord yeah it
looks like this was brought up by some
other hackers um who said hey you know
this isn't really my business but I
don't think this is right and um
somebody from H1 followed up and said
hey just so you know we're aware and
we're talking about this internally so
it's awesome to see um some some Swift
action on it I hope it wasn't that it
had to like be disclosed get to that
point it doesn't based on the report
like context within the report it
doesn't seem like there was any like
push back or mediation or anything like
that just seems like you know Beck's was
like thanks for the Bounty I would like
this disclosed so I can have it my Flex
sheet or whatever my brag sheet and uh
and uh then other people saw it and were
like hey hang on a second that's not
right so you should be flexing harder
yeah those muscles should be bigger you
know yeah absolutely so cool yeah did
have we talked so you mentioned HS M you
know uh you know chat on here have we
talked about that concept before on the
Pod I don't don't I don't know if we
have I don't think it's anything like
secret for what it's worth yeah no it's
it's there's a Blog I just pulled it up
right now on it so uh the hacker success
manager program I guess the hacker
success program is something that that
hacker one um sort of launched was it
2022 I think probably yeah a couple
years ago yeah maybe maybe 2021 uh but
essentially um I'm not sure what the
what the requirements are for you know
to be to enter the program but uh
there's a a couple hundred maybe three
400 hackers that uh have hacker success
managers and essentially it's a person
that works at hacker one U my I'm team
Steve freaking love Steve um you know
and they they're a point of contact for
the top hackers at hacker one to have a
conversation with them and and um just
kind of have the voice heard have a have
a you know point of contact for any any
issues that could pop up help setting
you know goals for what kind of bounties
you want to get or what what kind of
stats you want to do in a given year um
and and I've had a really good
experience with that program it's it's
increased my ability to uh deal with
issues faster on the platform it's it's
increased my ability to stay goal
oriented and focused on the platform so
big fan of that program I'm not sure if
bug crowd and integrity are running
similar programs but I would I would
hope that they are yeah absolutely yeah
I have
the same HSM Steve he's awesome and um
yeah nothing but good things to say
about it honestly it's uh it's I wish it
were more easily more easily scalable is
the only thing like I don't even see
like a potential solution or you could
scale it better and keep the
effectiveness of it it's really just one
of those things where um you know they
really value the top hackers and it
shows especially through the HSM program
I think it's amazing that like if I have
a problem with something I can always
just like reach out to a person and they
you know not just like sending a ticket
into the void or having to do mediation
or something I have an actual human that
I can talk to about it and um get candid
you know feedback or you know if I am
wrong on this or whatever you know Steve
has no problem telling me that so yeah
Steve definitely does not have any
problem telling you that I I definitely
have you know and I don't know the thing
about about Steve too is he's such a
great guy you know like and so I'll call
him I'll be like man I'm just like
really frustrated about this specific
vulnerability and you know all of this
stuff is like semicon stuff right so you
know you can't be you know talking about
all the details but it's good to be able
to talk to Steve and be like I'm really
frustrated with this he's like Justin
take a breath man like we're gonna get
it fixed out you know we're gonna we're
GNA work on it it's gonna get resolved
you know and just kind of you know and
so I don't have to send these sort of
angry messages to the teams you know
because it's an it's an emotional
process sometimes s when you put so much
hard work to to find a vulnerability you
found something you're really proud of
and then you know sometimes programs
don't see it's worth so it's definitely
uh improved my quality of experience
with hacker one since I've been on the
the U the
HSM in that program yeah absolutely it
it reminds me of the type of
communications that you get to have at
live hacking events where if you have a
problem you can like talk to a triage or
a hacker one employee or something and
just um you know that that that level of
transparency and uh willingness to
communicate and stuff is just really
really nice to see so it is indeed
anyways uh we very sidetracked there uh
I wanted to bring up because um this was
in the sheet and we were just talking
about Facebook um login stuff there was
this thread uh jsh medani I think
is than me yeah that's yeah j25 on uh on
Twitter or X or whatever um yeah he's
been doing a bunch of of different uh
Twitter threads recently which is nice
to see lots of you know good tips and
stuff in there and one that particularly
popped off was this one talking about um
an atto through Facebook login so
essentially he found this weird
mechanism where if you log in with
Facebook and you when you're logging in
through Facebook one of the things that
you can choose is that you can choose
not to share your email from your
Facebook profile so if you log in with
Facebook you can log in without Facebook
telling the service what your email
address is when you do that the service
would then ask what is your email uh you
know your new account or whatever give
us your email so you put in a victim
email and it would send uh email
confirmation link to the victim email
then if you log in a second time with
the same Facebook account and you do
share your email what ends up happening
is that it ties your the account on the
service to your Facebook account but
this time if you share your own email
that's linked to your Facebook account
it just sends the same email activation
link to the new email and so instead of
like you filling in your email or
whatever uh you basically just say you
know this is this is my email from
Facebook this time it sends the same
link to the new email and then you can
you know log in as the victim well I
think you actually the steps it to the
vitim right yeah so you rece it back to
the victim email you use the old link
that you got to then verify the account
and now you have access to a victim
account and uh he said he got 16k for uh
for that account takeover which is
really really hilarious I thought it was
even funnier because Tanner uh cash
money he uh he retweeted this tweet and
uh he you know understandable he he he
retweeted this tweet and was like uh he
was like oh it finally happened and
attached to the Tweet was this uh this
bug Bounty tip from
integrity 2019 okay so this is four
years a more than four years ago August
2019 and it uh it's a picture that says
signing up with Facebook remove the
email scope from The ooth Prompt and see
what happens at its cash money so it's h
it's really hilarious that uh you know
that
four-year-old uh tweet or tip or
whatever was basically the same exact
thing that was happening here and sure
enough it led to a nice big Bounty
that's that's sick man you know we we've
got some some content coming out soon on
like authentication related stuff and
we're going to talk about that a little
bit later today but Tanner is like the
king of that stuff man every time every
time I talk to Tanner about you know off
flows or weird [__] you know like race
conditions in the off you know he always
has some some crazy bug and this is such
an an great example of thinking outside
of the box in those scenarios like the
whole point of contacting Facebook in
the first place is to share the email
well what happens if I just don't share
the email yeah I love that that
functionality exist just throws a wrench
into everything it's so awesome yeah no
it's great and he definitely called this
shot and and good on uh jsh for you know
either remembering what Tanner said or
thinking of it himself and trying this
complex flow right because I feel like
when if I had done this and then it said
provide an email and I was like okay and
it sent a link I'd be like uh you know
this is probably just like the normal
email validation flow yeah but then he
he he you know continues to press deeper
he says all right well what if I you
know don't complete this whole flow go
back try it again is that the same email
you know and boom it is you know it's
the same code in the email so what a
what a what a baller and you know it's a
16k bounty too so that that is like you
know you know he found that on a
high-end program yeah and he said it was
an old it was an old report um where did
he say I think he he said cuz Tanner
replied to it and was like hey congrats
and he said thanks it's an old finding
just sharing some tips and tricks with
the community so 16k on an old finding
uh either they were already a high ping
program or that was a crazy Bounty for
whoever it was so that's a that's a
super super cool write up and a super
simple concept so I'm going to put that
in my little shovel shove that into my
little notebook of of tips to try out
when I I'm testing uh just gonna shove
it into the notebook of tips is that do
yeah yeah yeah I'm like a like a
restaurant worker all right oh yeah okay
I see that now I'm starting to see the
imagery um man for those of you that are
watching on YouTube rather than
listening I've got a little bit of a
cough right now and I just like hacked
up a lung while I was on mute during
that that last uh last uh Grant Joel was
on there so sorry about that for any of
you on YouTube but um yeah uh let with
that let's move to the last uh the last
news item that we wanted to talk about
um which which is uh a a write up from
uh canva actually uh from the security
team at canva talking about when URL
parsers disagree okay so we're going to
talk about this a little bit more later
today too but I read this right up and I
was like man this is such a cool thing
right um I love it
when this so let me let me get a little
bit more you know conceptual here okay
right uh you know one of the things we
talk about all time on this podcast is
trying to seed attack vectors right
trying to seed ideas in your brain of
what kind of vulnerabilities are
possible and what kind of things you can
try when you're attacking these
applications right and and you know once
these ideas excuse me once these ideas
get into your head um when you're
looking at applications you have the
opportunity or not to go and and try
them and the people that do try them and
they go through the effort to you know
learn whatever additional details they
need um those are the people that are
going to go far and that are going to
find a lot of crazy bugs okay so it's
just it's a little bit of a rant I
people have been asking me lately how do
we find you know high impact bugs you
got to try high impact attack vectors
okay yep so um rant over let let's talk
about the actual technical details of
this one um we've spent a lot of time on
the news section so uh I'm not going to
go too deep into this one but the tldr
of this writeup is that um there is a a
a disagreement as the title you know
says between two URL parsers in use in
the specific application okay and the
disagreement occurs when parsing a file
URL and the disagreement happens over
the role of the question mark character
okay um so so yeah as we know from from
URLs the question mark normally
delineates the start of the the query
right
um and is no part of the path well one
of the um one of the parsers in question
did not respect that right it said hey
the query
parameter or the question mark is just
another character in The Path because
it's a file scheme rather than a an
actual um uh rather than like an HTTP
scheme or something like this right so
because it's a file scheme which I would
technically say is more accurate yeah um
like I'm not sure if it should be the
same like I think context is kind of
appropriate here where like if it is a
file scheme then like technically the
only thing there should be a path so
like quy parameters and stuff shouldn't
it should never like be part of that
like if you're just generically parsing
a scheme then like okay I can see why
you
might I'd almost say mistakenly parse it
that way but context is kind of
important it is it is and and you're
actually I didn't have that in my notes
but you're you're right dude actually
you know I can go in here in my you know
Linux file system create a file with a
question mark in it right yeah I'm not
sure if you can do that on Windows or
not but um so in that scenario the
question mark should be uh you know
respected as a as a actual valid
character right yeah um and so but one
of the parsers in this in this situation
was mistakenly using the question mark
in actually truncating the path right
so when a malicious uh or when the the
checks were occurring of a certain URL
to say hey is this uh you know trying to
path Traverse out it would you know they
just had one dot and then the question
mark and it says nope this is just
referring to the current current
directory we're truncating everything
after the question mark all all good
here and then uh after that after that
question mark they had a series of path
reversals that would go back up and hit
you know Etsy password or whatever and
include it in the SVG file um and that's
because the second parser was looking at
that question mark not as a as a
truncating character as something that
will end the path but actually as a part
of the path and then allowing that part
of the path to be deleted by a path
traversal sequence to go back out and
grab that that that file from you know
another directory
so yeah it's it's such a great it's such
a great attack Vector here whenever
you're dealing with file URLs this can
definitely be something to check and
something that's going to be on my list
for sure or what did you say before I'm
going to take this take this tip and
stick it in my my tip tips folder yeah
this this is reminding me I don't know
why but this reminded me of the story
and honestly I was trying to find a
source for this I don't know if this is
true but I and I can't remember where I
heard it either but allegedly it goes
that the Creator do you know what glob
is glob like in Linux uh like the
concept that you can do like star and
like star star slash and that kind of
stuff and it basically does like
matching of of files so that that whole
system is called glob oh interesting and
the guy who created term for that yeah
yeah yeah it's like glob or globbing
basically like so the guy who created
that initially when he created it he
called it like asterisk like star. C and
after he finished writing it he uh he he
was he was like you know he was trying
to test
it and he was like you know RM star. C
and it deleted the actual star. C file
instead of like all the files that end
did so it deleted the source code and he
had to rewrite the entire thing from
memory oh gosh dude that's terrible what
what a terrible idea to name it Stardust
he deserved that you know for sure but I
know there are some um you know there
are some weird files right where like I
think this is like a try to hack me or
like some you know this is I'm really
reaching far back in the to my CTF days
when I was in in college but there was
some you know trivial little Pro thing
was like okay this this file has a bunch
of like weird characters in it and like
if you try to delete it just using like
tab completion it's like deletes
everything you know or like does a bunch
of crazy stuff and you can't remove this
file so there's definitely some weird
stuff with Linux like that where you've
got to like add two dashes you know it's
like rm- r or RM Dash Dash and then the
file name will like prevent it from
having other flags in the name or
something like that yeah yeah super
crazy stuff yeah anyways another little
tangent there but uh we're to you know
it has been you in a while so you know
we're just we're shaking off the dust
we're going down our little tangents
true all right you want to jump into the
M the main content uh of of URL
structures
here I do I do uh throat is giving me a
little little problems here but we'll
we'll push through it um okay
so today's topic a little bit uh you
know past the new section um is on URL
structuring and then a bunch of other
cool [__] uh this one's not gonna lie
this one's a little bit um scattered so
uh we'll see where we land um but this
uh episode was sort of um inspired by uh
a conversation that I had at a live
hacking event where one of the people at
the Live Hack men had found an open
redirect and was challenging another
person uh you and this open redirect
resulted in an account takeover and and
was challenging another person at the
live hacking event to see if they could
split it as
well excuse me um oh I recall this
happening yeah I think you there I was
watching this happen in real time yeah
yeah and and so it made me realize that
not everyone is familiar with all the
different parts of the URL um and so I I
kind of have this little graph here that
we'll we'll put up on the
screen um and uh it's missing one piece
which is the path parameters but this is
a pretty good breakdown of all the
different parts of a
URL all right so
Joel look look at this look at this
graph I'm trying to and I
I'm is this okay so I I thought that
this was like a pretty a thing that most
people were super familiar with would
you say that you are super familiar with
every single one of these or no I'm
definitely I know what all of these are
and what they're called I'm confused at
how to read this graph yes I knew I knew
about every single part of this okay so
for those of you listening the average
URL has one 2 three four five six seven
eight I would say nine Parts okay um so
the first part at the very left hand
side is the scheme right okay this is
going to be your HTTP https sort of
thing right um this could be file this
could be uh you know all FTP could be
all sorts of things there's a great um
resource called the ssrf Bible that was
floating around years ago that would
talk about if you have an
ssrf here are some cool things you can
do with alternative schemes like FTP and
gopher and that sort of thing um so the
scheme is really important okay but most
people know about the scheme most people
don't know about the next part
apparently which is the username and
password fields which you can put in the
URL but but you were familiar with this
Joel yeah I mean these are user password
is something that I use like all the
time if it's like an open redirect
bypass because usually there's like a
starts with or ends with or maybe
they're they're parsing it incorrectly I
mean this happens on Android too where
um there's like different bypasses uh
depending on how it's formatted if
they're special characters or really in
like a like a in in like a deep link
scheme or uh yeah I mean just with like
the default U.P parse there's um there's
a great
uh report like self disclosure report or
whatever
fromg yeah yeah the gold uh the golden
techniques for bypassing URL parsing and
he talks a little bit about that and
there's some very big Nuance between
like android.net.uri and java.net.uri I
I think they're the the two classes but
yeah definitely go check that out we'll
put we'll put a link down below yeah
yeah definitely drop that in the doc we
we want to get that on the on the
description but the next thing that
comes in in a possible URL is the user
in pass field okay so the user is um you
can type anything after the colon SL
slash right so scheme slash then you've
got user colon password at now I think
that this is sort of like a and when I
say at I mean the ad sign right so this
is sort of a legacy thing sort of left
over I believe from when um they used to
specify basic off this way so you could
actually a lot of stuff still does this
really yeah yeah so so if you go to a
website and you get um a a realm
response like it it'll say like Realm uh
what's what's the specific verbiage
actually stumbled on one of these Bearer
realm equals or whatever it'll basically
pop up a box on your it looks like an
alert box and it has a username and a
password though uses basic off doesn't
it it uses it creates an authorization
header with basic and then it as a as a
basic C4 encoded username and password
in that doesn't it yep yeah but it's
equivalent yeah yeah it absolutely is
equipment that's true um and and you
know it'd be really cool if you could
kind of smuggle these sort of things in
there um like for example if you could
if you could like have someone click a
link and force their browser to do you
know auth authorization with basic but I
believe they it was it's been disabled
um in all modern browsers but you can
fact check me on that while I'm while
I'm explaining this next section Joel if
you would
um yeah so the the main reason I want to
mention this is this user and pass
section is super helpful
for uh bypassing restrictions on a
domain right because for for example
because you can go
httpgoogle
docomo at test.com right and that that
that URL is going to go to test.com
right and you could say all right you
could just prepend it to a uh you know
in a subdomain of of test.com and sure
you could do that but there are a lot of
scenarios where if it it treats this
user in what the the URL parsing Library
will treat this username and password
field differently okay and and and then
then a subdomain attached to the domain
um and they sometimes I've even seen
them treat the username and password
field different from each other even
though that they're um you know separate
entities uh or same a part of that same
prior to the at symbol um structure that
comes in the URL so very important for
us to be aware of the existence of this
user and password thing if you're
looking to bypass uh uh you know any
sort of open redirect uh restrictions
okay so I've done a little reading and
from what I can tell uh I'm on a stack
Overflow post from 2011 2012 okay and
basically it starts out the original
answer says that yes you can indeed put
username call and password at host.com
and it will send those credentials in a
standard authorization header then if
you look through the comments people say
oh this functionality doesn't doesn't
work anymore and they link to a ticket
from 2011 on a chromium like bug ticket
that's like a this doesn't work anymore
okay couple comments down ah actually
this does work it's just IE where this
doesn't work oh this doesn't work as of
2019 it works in chrome doesn't work in
Safari May 2020 doesn't work in Firefox
Chrome or Safari November 2022 doesn't
work in Chrome Works in in curl and
Postman TW uh May of this year Works in
chromium so I don't actually I don't
actually know are you Kidd um I can't
seem to find a solid answer and I'm not
getting enough info just by requesting
it
inur I mean.com you know maybe it's
something that maybe it's like uh only
feature or something but yeah I was
almost certain that you could put
username call and password and it would
rewrite the URL to put it in an offhe
header because that allows you to visit
uh sites that would require realm off
normally normally you can just rewrite
it
um yeah I thought I I was pretty sure
this was a thing so we might have to
test this or maybe if somebody from the
audience knows I tried it I tried it I
tried it in chromium or in not chromium
in Chrome um and it doesn't work in CHR
Chrome as far as I can tell uh just from
looking at the inspector real quick um
would be very interested to know if that
was the case because it would be really
interesting if you could have someone go
to a link off them into the link you
know let's say you have a um an API
right that's doing authorization via VIA
you know that isn't looking to see
whether the they well we're we're
grasping now I I think but let's say
they're looking at whether it says
authorization Bearer or op authorization
basic right and then it just takes the
token afterward and parses it you could
actually potentially smuggle that in via
the URL if it's a b64 encoded token
let's say it's like a like a JWT or
something like that right you might be
able to actually smuggle that in there
and force the victim to Au is you and
sometimes API requests have like um you
know cookies that they will set on the
response or like uh maybe you can
trigger an xss if the response is if the
response uh content type is not
specified or whether it's text HTML or
something so there's a lot of
exploitation scenarios there that that
could be you know reached if this wasn't
was actually working very interesting
that it says it's working in chromium
though okay so more info Mozilla
docs say under live research here HP
authentication the very very bottom it
says access using credentials in the URL
many clients allow you to avoid the
login prompt by using an encoded URL
containing the username and password
like this username Co and password at
www.example.com the use of these URLs is
deprecated in Chrome the username col
and password at part of a URL is even
stripped out for security reasons and
they actually link to that same Chrome
bug from 2011 they really and it's it
says in Firefox it is checked if the
site actually requires authentication
and if not Firefox will warn the user
with a prompt saying you're about to log
into the site whatever with username
whatever but it doesn't require
authentication they may be trying to
trick you um so that's really
interesting I'm going to send you a link
to this and we'll put a link to this in
the uh in the docs or down below on the
in the notes as well but yeah super
interesting this is this is really I
wonder if it's yeah Firefox is doing
something weird with it so wonder how
being said I don't know about Safari I
don't know about iedge or any of these
other you know Edge browsers I say Edge
browsers all these these um browsers
that are on the periphery of the of the
you know primary browser scene that use
I me let's not forget right Safari and
Edge together make up 25% of the browser
market so it's pretty significant if if
you know they're vulnerable to this uh
and they're not following the same
standards as Chrome which I think is St
they chromium
right uh I think it might now yeah uh
which should that after yeah yeah
absolutely well we came here to teach
and look we are being taught
um uh so Mor of the story there
definitely some interesting stuff
surrounding the username and password
field in the URL um one quick tip that I
will add here is that um one of the most
common bypasses that I see to domain
validation here is when you add
something to the URL right uh you know
add a a username that contains a
backslash okay so oftentimes that will
be reflected so you know you'll see
something like https col test.com back
slash you know victim.com right yep um
and that backslash will actually break
the the at the um username and and
password field there and will be
actually rendered by the browser as
test.com rather than at example.com um
or you know victim.com or whatever so
that is a very useful escape to sort of
find open redirects or uh you know
bypass uh URL validation uh in an
application yeah simply just putting it
a back slash in there yeah yeah yeah um
very very cool stuff there um next
section everyone knows it's the it's the
domain the subdomain the domain that
sort of part and then there's one extra
part after that right Joel one one part
that isn't always visible and that
is the fragment no no Joel come on look
at the graph
man look at the graph it's the port the
port okay it's the purple part okay so
so so
um so so the after the domain you put a
you put a a [__] right and then you're
able to specify a port we see this all
the time you know if you're trying to
hit Port 880 or whatever you got to go
to Local Host col 880 to specify the
port trying to hit sometimes when you're
trying to bypass um you know URL
validation it is also helpful to inject
illegal characters here because um you
know even just putting an A or something
like that in there and if it gets passed
through there's some weird stuff that
can happen here so definitely check that
out as well yeah another thing that's
interesting that we've actually done in
security interviews is
tlds um so something common like yeah
big mistake that you see all the time is
that whoever invented Rex came up with
the brilliant idea that the dot is a
wild card character yeah which is
amazing minus the fact that so much of
Internet infrastructure uses dots as uh
separator character and so this often
leads to bad rexes where they put a dot
in but they should have put a backs
slash dot for a literal dot not just any
character and this leads to all sorts of
different uh vulnerabilities and things
that can pop up as a result of being
able to manipulate either the TLD or the
or the root domain or the root domain
and the TLD or you know something to
that effect uh to to get it to parse
incorrectly yeah yeah no especially if
you're hacking sites like um you know
for when I lived in Japan you we're
looking at some code. JP sites right so
whatever. co.jp right you got an extra
dot in there that they don't always
Escape and if you can you know inject a
a um for example if they they don't
escape the the dot that comes Co
whatever whatever JP is likely a valid
domain right because JP is also a a
valid domain correct so um you know
there's lots of ways that you can kind
of tweak that you also see that for
.co.uk
um and us as well us but there's no cod.
us which is weird it's it's one of those
like the the country ones that like
there's C UK and.uk and. co.jp and. JP
and I think there's a couple other that
are like that but then the US is just us
yeah I don't know why yeah maybe we just
have I don't is that a us you know is
that origin or clim it man [__] right
it's ours
now America it's a peak American
Metal I made this yeah I made this this
is dang it Joel you're making me call
because you're making me laugh man um
all right so the port section definitely
try to inject some stuff there then we
get into the path the query and the
fragment which most I think most people
know about right you got the path you're
breaking down you know slash asset sljs
you know whatever JS and you got the
query parameters right question mark x
equals 1 and then you got the fragment
right the hash the hash is not ever sent
to the server side so when you're
interacting with serers side things
sometimes you send the hash and it
truncates stuff it does weird stuff this
is a great a great way to truncate the
right side uh of your injection if
you're um able to do an ssrf
vulnerability where something is getting
tacked on the end right like a like a
file extension or something like that
it's basically like a comment in a URL
right like in the sense that it makes
everything after it just not like do
anything right like dude kind of like
SQL
injection Joel I love this I love this
way of thinking that you have it's like
this is this is a comment in the
URL I mean I never thought about it that
way man I'm just I'm just looking at you
in awe when you say stuff like that so
yeah it's like a comment for the URL
sure uh and the the um the you know the
browser is the only piece that's
actually really supposed to be able to
access that sort of thing um but if you
send a you know a fragment as a part of
a a request say you send a raw get
request weird stuff can happen most of
the time it's it's pulled out you know
before it even
reaches uh before it's processed by the
server so the last thing that I wanted
to mention that is not actually present
in this diagram that we that we have uh
is this thing called The Path parameter
um you've seen these before right uh
yeah yeah yeah uh orange did a talk
about this at Defcon a couple years ago
yeah yeah so the the famous you know dot
dot semic thing that's that's utilizing
this sort of path parameter notation so
um you know let's say you've got a path
it's like whatever.com
test and you put a semicolon right then
you can start adding parameters there
xal 1 you know and and those those will
and I believe it's another semicolon
delimiter so semicolon x equals you know
two or Y 2 you can start adding
parameters there this is only parsed by
some type typ of um some types of
servers uh in some languages uh because
of that it can cause
interoperability uh problems right which
is what we saw with the the orange s dot
dot semi semicolon thing because does
that get parsed as a a path that is dot
do semicolon or does that get parsed as
dot dot of the path traversal sequence
or a plus an empty you know path
parameter string yeah um so there's
definitely some weird [__] that happens
there um it's important to know all of
these different pieces of the of the URL
I think so you can come up with weird
attack Victors like orange did yeah
absolutely and I I love these talks he's
actually given two of them I I just
realized I was confusing one with the
other one but he's he did two talks in
2017 and 2018 both about URL parsing um
which just shows you the the level that
he goes to which is always awesome to
see um so we'll link both of those below
but definitely if you haven't seen these
or you haven't read them or if you
haven't read it in a while read it
because it's it's always good to just
revisit that and be like you know this
is probably still a thing you know just
like we talked about earlier with uh
with Tanner's tip from 2019 like these
things they uh they persist they they
don't just uh disappear because somebody
made a post or a talk about it they cool
to see it's really cool to see people
call stuff too you know like we we we
recently recorded an episode with fron
which I think will Air after this
episode um Y and you know he was calling
stuff from like you know way back there
that's still hyper relevant and and and
I would say is still you know some of
the some of the peak parts of the
industry um and so yeah definitely pay
attention to these to these people that
are that are you know dropping some
research this is why I have a tips
folder see this is this is the great the
tips fold the the notes.txt the you know
cat everything in notes.txt exactly the
10 year long notes.txt
exactly exactly exctly all right um so
cool yeah the last thing I I really had
on this list here was like uh you know I
was going to ask you actually uh about
how this looks for for Android and stuff
like that specifically in the in the
context of ooth related stuff have you
have you ever looked at like ooth flows
that use a specific client ID you know
that that client ID is associated with
the app right you know so that it's
redirecting the redirect U is configured
to be the app and then there being some
sort of rex related issues or um domain
related issues with
that um so uh I'm sure it exists I'm
trying to think of a specific example
with like ooth but generally speaking
yeah all the time you see like URL
parsing problems which circles me back
to the baggy Pro um blog posts about uh
host validation parsing on Android and
the different bypasses and the different
pitfalls and gotas and whatever's
related to that just even if you're
using the wrong class to parse it um you
know you can have pitfalls there so that
that stuff definitely exists for sure
especially with Rex um I can even think
of personal bugs that I found that have
been like you know they did dot ends
with or whatever instead of you know
they forgot a DOT at the beginning um or
something uh but yeah the Android
oftentimes it is very similar to what
you described where you'll log in and
it'll redirect you to a URI schema that
will then you know send the code back
it'll just launch the app directly and
it'll get the code through some ooth
Handler um that can be a lot harder to
exploit because typically it's the code
flow where B like the off code flow
where basically you're just you log in
and then it generates a code for you and
that just gets sent directly back to the
app and it just you know makes a claim
and gets your off token exchanges it for
off token um so there's a lot less room
for error in a setup like that but that
doesn't mean that you can't explo it or
use it for your own purposes I think it
would be really Case by case I was kind
of I was kind of thinking like you know
it would be kind of interesting if well
I don't know because then you wouldn't
have a scheme and I guess it would kind
of get parsed as a as a relative URL
probably but I I was thinking it'd be
interesting if there was a an app that
said okay uh we're just going to allow
it to redirect to test
appon right that's like the custom
scheme that they've registered in the
app right and and that was the whole was
test appon right and then you know you
could actually do test appon and then
you know the password at test.com right
that us utilizing that username and
password you know there's some synergies
there um that that piece in the URL um
and then you know maybe get it
redirected to your domain instead of to
uh the actual Android app but I imagine
if it has to start with the AC character
I believe that the browser would
probably try to treat that as a relative
URL if there's no uh if there's no HTTP
or recognized scheme in the beginning so
I'm not sure that there's much Synergy
that's possible there yeah now that
being said like the way
that they get registered on Android is
it's within the Android manifest so you
say like everything under this scheme
potentially with this host and this port
and this path or whatever should all go
to my app but you can also do that for
HTTP and https so you can register like
a specific HTTP or https URL and host
and say I want this URL to be openable
in my app and it should do something you
can but you can do what you said like
you I could make just a scheme with no
host or what like anything after it be
loaded in my app and then those are the
cases where you're going to look and see
are they parsing it correctly because it
steps beyond the system into the app and
then there's chance that they're they're
handling something incorrectly I I
imagine that the
um that the the SE uh that the colon
character is not a valid character for
you to have in your registered schemes
right yeah not direct I mean maybe it is
I I don't know specifically what it have
to the spec on that yeah yeah you'd have
to look at the spec like like here's
what I'm thinking right you got like
test app colon that's what the ooth um
redirector configuration is is set to so
what if you and then it takes anything
after that so you do you know test St
colon 1 23 you know without putting a SL
a slash in there right it would be
interesting if you could do um test you
could register an app called test app
colon you know hacked colon SL slash
right you know that that would be your
scheme and then um you know then you
could hijack that aath code coming into
your malicious app but I I I kind of
highly doubt that Android's going to
allow a a colon into the into the actual
name of the scheme yeah it's one of
those things where even testing it is
very difficult because there's probably
multiple layers where it's being checked
um like a couple live hacking events ago
I was looking at an Android app um and
we were trying to well it was actually a
service that took Android app like APK
files and then we like parse them and
handle them and so we thought oh why
don't we just like put an xxe in the
Android manifest and then when it pulls
the app name out it'll you know pop the
xxc on the server side well the problem
is that Android manifests are written in
this Android XML which is like a binary
version of XML and it's like custom
encoded down is that do you know if it's
inflated or deflated XML is that what it
is it's it's not like a it's called it's
axml yeah for Android and so it like has
like a specific subset of things that it
supports and all this kind of stuff and
so we we were doing a bunch of testing
and all we ended up getting xxe one on
was like all of the local tooling that
we were using like to try and compile
like or decompile the APK like I would
get like an XX
in like it it it would never be like
exactly where I wanted it to because all
of the tooling and stuff that would be
used to like expand it or resign it or
whatever was getting vulnerable instead
of the actual XML that would then get
parsed and yeah I'm not sure if you were
using you know the name of that tool
that we might have to bleep as a as a
filler but uh if you actually do have
that you might report that to like you
know internet project or something like
that cuz who knows that that could cause
problems true that's true I actually I
do
Wonder critical critical critical
thinking man it might be a zero day we
might have to cut that out y well we
might have to bleep that but uh yeah no
I I think I think there's some going
back to the ooth flow you know with the
defined direct uh redirect your eyes I
think there is some wiggle room there um
but you'd have to have a really weird
configuration for example if if a um you
know if a uh identity provider was
setting the redirect URI to have to
include you know the first part of it
has to be test app right or whatever the
name of their scheme is and it doesn't
have a colon afterwards then you could
register a Handler called test app
hacked col slash right register that own
scheme in your malicious app and then
redirect to that which would which would
give you access to that that code that
you need to to take over the account so
you could still you could still trigger
some some ooth um issues there uh via
redirect on mobile as well yeah yeah
definitely all right man uh let's see
let's see what else we got on the list
okay so like I said this one's all over
the place but um that kind of covers the
the URL parsing stuff that I wanted to
talk about um I just also wanted to talk
about some other Concepts that have kind
of been banging around in my head from
the live hacking events that we've been
to over the past couple months um and
you know there's just been lots of good
discussions with hackers and and one of
the ones that that came into my my brain
was was this concept of shared Secrets
across environments you know um and
specifically JWT related things um if
you have a a JWT signing secrets that's
shared across multiple environments and
you're giving people you're allowing
people to register on one environment
with an email and then you can use that
same token because it passes validation
on a different app you know I have no
idea what you're talking about right now
I've never seen that exact I've never
seen that exact bug
uh on oh really maybe well I was talking
to someone specific about this sort of
bug um you know at at a live hacking
event but yeah essentially the bug was
that you know there was a stage
environment you could sign up for you'd
get a JWT you could use that same JWT on
the prod environment um so let's say
you've got an account registered you
know Joel at jo.com right I could go to
the staging environment register Joel
dojo.com you know if there's not email I
am being sarcastic right now because
there everyone I I don't know if you're
like playing in on this but yes there
was it this exact same thing on it
wasn't staging but it was just that you
could like log into certain apps and
then any app within that same like they
use the same off mechanism like
middleware whatever across all their
things yeah you see it you know you see
it at at on various targets uh you know
I wasn't I mean what was that sarcasm
was that like are you saying because it
exists CU that was almost the exact bug
that I was just talking about as well
with
it was the same Target and it was
utilizing that bug oh what the heck I
did not hear about this this is crazy
okay okay I didn't yeah yeah so there
was an off by to get into one of these
tools yeah this is more prevalent than
expected I think because this is this is
you know multiple live hacking events
over the past year that that has had you
know this issue pop up on a Harden
Target like a Live Hack event Target so
definitely something we see and what was
sort of on my radar cuz we talked about
Cookie Monster in the past right that
uses sort of um you know that kind of
has a similar situation where it's like
okay you know maybe you can forge this
JWT but the ReUse of that JWT wasn't
really on my radar until this past year
quite as much yeah and honestly like
from a from an engineering perspective I
totally see why it's happening because
there's more and more push to centralize
all these sorts of off mechanisms into
one place and have like a single single
mechanism that's doing all the
authentication in a standardized way
which means that have more risk for
somebody to be able to issue an off
token that's just valid unless that
single Central off mechanism is really
really strictly properly checking like
where did this come from is it
specifically authorized for this other
application that they're trying to use
it on more than is it valid and is it
like validly signed and all that kind of
stuff because all that stuff could be
true but it could be for some other
service and it could still pass it's
actually similar to the uh to the thing
we were just talking about uh you know
before when when you're reusing
tokens across different different
providers too right like the the
Facebook thing where where they're not
checking the app ID associated with it
right um because it's actually a token
for a different provider but you know it
kind of all checks out so uh there
there's there's definitely reoccurring
themes that we see across these
authentication bugs which the more and
more you familiarize yourself with them
you'll you'll start looking for those uh
attack vectors which that's been kind of
a way I've I've grown as a hacker over
the past couple years is like um
authentication related bugs can be
really scary and sometimes I feel like
I'm forced down that route because the
other scope is so [__] you know it's
like all right might as well just look
it off and then when you do some crazy
bugs can come out of that so yeah and
it's weird because like I almost never
look at off a lot of the time because
it's such a weird it's such a weird flow
and you can end up sinking a lot of time
there and it's like a lot of times it's
like a weird setup stage where there's
very like limited restricted amount of
data and the program even if you submit
it they'll be like oh well this is just
during the registration flow so unless
the impact is like elsewhere within the
application oftentimes it doesn't even
like really count or it's not a high
enough impact um but yeah like you said
when you get backed into those Corners
where where it's a tight scope I mean we
just saw at the last event lots of off
stuff that was just like you know small
scope where do you look but you know you
you also look at the at the hackers that
pop crits on a regular basis right you
look at Sam herb you look at oacb you
look at some of these guys that make a
habit of looking at o every single
time they they always pop stuff man they
always [__] and so um yeah that's
something that I've sort of resolved to
look into a little bit more um and and
on that you know on that note uh I I was
going to talk a little bit about um one
of the uh sort of successes I've had in
this Arena which is um uh finding or I
guess looking at o which is multiactor
authentication bypasses and there's lots
of like you know super crappy multiactor
authentication bypasses where you can
like just navigate to the page or like
you know there's some some some um you
know other tricks you can do but one of
the things that I kind of wanted to
highlight is like especially when you've
got a flow where there's multiple M you
know multiactor devices like hey you
know do I want to send a text message to
the phone or do I want to get an email
or do I want to get a push you know
these systems get really complex and
these objects these um devices they're
just objects in the application and
they're vulnerable to stuff like idor
just like every other object in the in
the application could be right so um you
know I remember taking a deep dive at a
target one time and and kind of um
looking at this flow and finding an idor
in the multiactor authentication flow
it's just allowed me to use an attacker
controlled device to authenticate into
to the victim's account and and you
could use that to get account takeover
via the password reset flow and it was
like I can't believe that this actually
worked so you you'd think that I would I
would learn my lesson after that you
know to like keep actually look at
authentication more often but you know
sometimes it just doesn't S in that's
awesome that's awesome and you didn't
even say the word rate limiting I'm so
proud of you oh yeah that's true rate
limiting yeah I said dumb multiactor
bypasses like just navigating to the
thing anyway I was waiting for you say
rate limied cuz that's like the that's
like the go-to MFA bypass which is that
you can Brute Force OTP codes it's
screwed so many companies too if you can
figure out a way to to you know yeah
definitely Facebook pays a lot of money
for that yeah yeah they've paid
multiple mid to high five figure crits I
believe for that that bug that
specifically yep ridiculous yeah all
right man um let's see what else we got
here uh the only the last thing that I
wanted to go was um also related to O
stuff and it and
it's what else could it be on the on the
only other thing that uh you know is
left in the O mechanism which is uh you
know social media logins kind of like we
were talking about before um you know if
you're able to find you know some weird
provider that you don't see on a regular
basis yeah yeah or or maybe Well Log In
you shouldn't say that we're gonna have
to bleep that um you know log in with
some weird provider right let's just say
um it's always helpful to make sure that
those emails are associated with um you
know that that email is being validated
if you can get an account and off into a
a certain you know service provider via
the identity provider with an account
that doesn't have a validated email that
is a huge problem and can often result
in account takeover so keep these keep
these things in your head as you're
hacking um it can result in sort of
crazy bugs Yeah the more login
mechanisms the more chaos there is that
that's what I've learned the more room
for air because everybody does it a
little bit differently and yeah for sure
all right Joel do you want you know it's
already turning into a good a good
length episode you want to talk about
this report or you want to push it to
the next time uh yeah I'll make that
your call all right my voice is dying
let's let's let's call it a rra all
right all right we'll have some good
bugs to talk about next time all right
sounds good peace everybody
[Music]
peace